Citizens of Oz.
there's been 12 tide turns
since the Wicked Witch of the West
escaped with our Grimmerie.
Shield your children.
Trust no animals.
She will be eliminated.
Until then. the Wizard's vision
for the Oz of tomorrow marches on.
Do it. Move!
-Load it up.
-Come on. Let's go! Move!
No speaking.
The Wizard needs the road finished.
Move it! Move it!
Come on. let's move!
Fill up that basket!
Keep moving.
Come on.
Come on. Keep moving.
Get up!
Come on!
Settle down!
Whoa. whoa. whoa. whoa.
Get back!
Retreat! Guards. retreat!
It's the Witch!
The Witch! She's back!
♪ Every day. more Wicked ♪
♪ Every day. the terror grows ♪
♪ All of Oz is ever on alert ♪
♪ That's the way with Wicked ♪
♪ Spreading fear where'er she goes ♪
♪ Seeking out new victims she can hurt ♪
♪ Like some terrible green blizzard ♪
♪ Throughout the land. she flies ♪
♪ Defaming our poor Wizard
With her calumnies and lies ♪
♪ She lies ♪
Go. go!
Release them!
♪ Save us from the Wicked ♪
♪ Shield us so we won't be hexed! ♪
♪ Give us warning
Where will she strike next? ♪
♪ Where will she strike next? ♪
♪ When I stop the Wizard ♪
♪ All Oz will applaud ♪
♪ How I saved them from the Wizard ♪
♪ By revealing he's a fraud ♪
♪ If I can just make them
Believe in the truth ♪
♪ That all that he says is a lie ♪
♪ That's when they'll finally bid
The Wizard goodbye ♪
-Come with me.
-What?
To meet the Wizard.
The Wizard will see you now.
♪ Dearest Glinda. you are still the best ♪
Well. I guess.
♪ Others are Good
But you're the Goodliest ♪
♪ We feel merry. we feel cheery
Just to gaze on your reflection ♪
♪ Only you disprove the theory
That you can't improve perfection ♪
Thank you.
Good. Good. Good. Good. Good.
Good.
She's so good.
Glinda the Good.
♪ La. la. la. la ♪
♪ La. la. la. la. la. la. la
La. la. la. la. la. la. la. la. la ♪
♪ Save us from the Wicked ♪
♪ Every night our voices wail ♪
♪ Save us from this fear and victimhood ♪
♪ We believe in Glinda ♪
♪ With her magic. she'll prevail ♪
♪ She will make it end the way it should ♪
♪ When at last the Wicked is defeated ♪
♪ By the Good ♪
♪ The Good ♪
♪ Wicked is defeated. ♪
♪ By the Good ♪
There's a quoncert in Quox.
if you wanna attend. next week.
Oh. perhaps.
The Quadling Quorum wants to honor you.
They're just not sure for what yet.
Good to hear.
And someone sent pastries.
-Good for us.
-Send these to my hovel. please.
The gowns from last week?
Oh. maybe. uh.
give to the under-fortunate.
-Oh. of course.
-Good idea.
You know. while we're at it.
we really should look into
trademarking the word "good."
-Ooh!
-Oh!
That's go-- I mean. I'm goosified.
My follicles are screaming.
I love my job so much.
Oh. good
Madame Morrible.
Forgive me for keeping you waiting.
I had no idea.
Has something happened? Is it Elphaba?
You mean the Wicked Witch.
Right. of course.
Come in. come in.
Mrs. Morrible. I can--
Would you like us to take minutes for you?
I can get you. like. a little snack.
You want a little snack?
Like a cherry frazzle or a juice puff?
"Mrs. Morrible"? She's not married.
You shut...
With the Yellow Brick Road grand opening ahead
and the Wicked Witch attacks
growing bolder.
the public is on edge.
So it's more important than ever
that you lift everyone's spirits.
as only you can.
Accordingly.
Oh. Madame. I love it.
What is it?
Your new mode of transport.
Your very own vehicular spherical globule.
So. like. a bubble?
Sure.
Was that supposed to happen?
It's all right.
Are you sure?
Does that do what I think it does?
No!
I can't.
No way!
I'm obsessulated.
The Wizard had it crafted
especially for you.
His Ozness feels it vital that you.
as our Good Witch.
also be airborne.
I agree.
But don't fret over your inability
to produce any actual magic.
This invention will
disguise your deficiency.
The Bubble's mechanism
is cleverly concealed.
People will assume
that you are causing it to float
through your own witchly powers.
So. just let them assume.
Right.
But don't forget this.
The wand really sells it.
I'll see you at the opening ceremony.
Thank you so much.
A magic wand?
Happy birthday. Galinda!
It's what I've wanted most of all.
Come on. give it a go.
Yeah. try it out!
-Magic! Magic! Magic! Magic!
-Come on!
Oh.
I forgot to say the spell.
-Oh. yeah. Come on. Yeah. Yeah.
-Makes sense.
I hereby commandify
that something magical shall happen!
She can't even make a spark.
Look.
There's a rainbow.
What is that?
Did you make that?
Um...
Well. you know how I love rainbows.
-Oh. wow.
-Do it again!
That's my friend!
I knew she could do it.
-Go see the rainbow!
-Isn't it fantastic?
I knew she had magic.
Who is ready for some cake?
What's wrong. dearest?
You got everything you wanted.
I know. but I wanna be magical.
For real. And...
I'm not.
Oh. but. darlingest.
everyone loves you.
Believe me.
that's all you'll ever need.
Where's that smile?
That's my girl.
Sweetheart. you coming?
Come on!
Glinda!
Fellow Ozians.
Good news.
Now. at last.
all roads lead to the Wizard.
♪ Oh. what a celebration
We'll have today ♪
♪ Thank Goodness ♪
♪ Let's have a celebration
The Glinda way ♪
♪ Thank Goodness ♪
♪ Finally. a day that's totally
Wicked Witch-free ♪
♪ We couldn't be happier ♪
♪ Thank Goodness ♪
Thank Goodness for you. Glinda.
and your handsome swain. Prince Fiyero.
newly appointed captain of the Gale Force.
assembled by the Wizard himself
to capture the Wicked Witch.
Tell us. Captain. How does it feel?
It's frustrating.
But I became captain to find her.
and I will keep on searching until I do.
No!
Being engaged.
We're engaged?
Surprised?
Yes.
Good. We hoped you'd be.
The Wizard and I.
Aw.
♪ We couldn't be happier
Right. dear? ♪
♪ Couldn't be happier
Right here ♪
♪ Look what we've got
A fairy-tale plot ♪
-♪ Our very own happy ending ♪
-Aw.
♪ Where we couldn't be happier
True. dear? ♪
♪ Couldn't be happier. ♪
♪ And we're happy to share
Our ending vicariously ♪
♪ With all of you ♪
♪ He couldn't look handsomer ♪
♪ I couldn't feel humbler. ♪
♪ We couldn't be happier ♪
♪ Because happy is what happens ♪
♪ When all your dreams come true ♪
And. Glinda. dear. we are happy for you.
As Press Secretary.
I've striven to ensure that all of Oz
knows the story of your braverism
in the face of the terrifying
Wicked Witch of the West.
♪ I hear she has an extra eye
That always remains awake ♪
♪ I hear that she can shed her skin
As easily as a snake ♪
♪ I hear some rebel animals
Are giving her food and shelter ♪
♪ I hear her soul is so unclean
Pure water can melt her ♪
♪ Melt her! ♪
♪ Please. somebody go and melt her! ♪
People are so empty-headed.
they'll believe anything.
If you'll excuse us just a clock tick.
Come with me. dearest.
What is going on?
People are watching.
I can't just stand there grinning.
pretending to go along with all this.
Do you think I like hearing them say
those awful things about her? I hate it.
Then what are we doing here? Let's go.
Let's go. Let's just get out of here.
I can't.
I can't when there are people
looking to me to raise their spirits.
You can't leave...
because you can't resist this.
That's the truth.
Well. maybe I can't.
Is that so wrong?
I mean. who could?
Well. you know who could.
We both know who could and who has.
And I have to find her. because
if someone else gets there first. she--
Fiyero. I'm worried for her too.
And miss her.
Can't you see
she doesn't want to be found?
You've got to face it.
She's made her choice.
You're right.
And look...
if it makes you happy.
of course I'll marry you.
It'll make you happy too. right?
You know me. I'm always happy.
Fiyero.
Thanks plenty. dearest.
He's. um..
-He's gone to fetch me a refreshment.
-Aw!
He's so thoughtful that way.
♪ That's why I couldn't be happier ♪
♪ No. I couldn't be happier ♪
♪ Though it is. I admit ♪
♪ The tiniest bit ♪
♪ Unlike I anticipated ♪
♪ But I couldn't be happier ♪
♪ Simply couldn't be happier ♪
♪ Well. not "simply" ♪
♪ 'Cause getting your dreams
It's strange. but it seems ♪
♪ A little. well. complicated ♪
♪ There's a kind of a sort of cost ♪
♪ There's a couple of things get lost ♪
♪ There are bridges you cross
You didn't know you crossed ♪
♪ Until you've crossed ♪
♪ And if that joy. that thrill ♪
♪ Doesn't thrill like you think it will ♪
♪ Still ♪
♪ With this perfect finale ♪
♪ The cheers and the ballyhoo ♪
♪ Who wouldn't be happier? ♪
♪ So I couldn't be happier ♪
♪ Because happy is what happens ♪
♪ When all your dreams come true ♪
♪ Well. isn't it? ♪
♪ Happy is what happens ♪
♪ When your dreams come true ♪
♪ We love you. Glinda
If we may be so frank ♪
♪ Thank Goodness ♪
♪ For all this joy
We know who we've got to thank ♪
♪ Thank Goodness ♪
♪ That means the Wizard. Glinda ♪
♪ And fiancé ♪
♪ They couldn't be Goodlier ♪
♪ She couldn't be lovelier ♪
♪ We couldn't be luckier ♪
♪ I couldn't be happier ♪
♪ Thank Goodness ♪
♪ Today ♪
♪ Thank Goodness for today ♪
It's the Wicked Witch! Take cover!
Mount up!
Glinda! Take cover. everyone!
Everyone. please.
Don't be alarmed.
She won't hurt you. It's okay.
She wants to kill us all!
Look!
Gale Force. go!
-Fiyero!
-Hyah!
Come on. Hyah!
No. come.
Move!
Halt!
Captain. do you see anything?
No.
Come on.
We must not rest
until we capture that Wicked Witch.
Come on! Let's go!
-Let's move out.
-Fall in.
Fiyero.
Even you.
Madame Governor?
That proposed new regulation.
the Animal Anti-Motility law.
What law?
Animals would need a permit to travel.
Munchkinland is the one place
in Oz it hasn't been ratified.
The League of Governors
is urging you to sign.
Nessa. you're not going to sign that.
But if I don't...
people will say.
"She's just like her sister."
Give us a clock tick. Avaric.
Boq...
Forgive me. It's just that
Elphaba abandoned me when I needed her.
She didn't even come see me
when Father died.
Only you did that.
Oz only knows how I'd have coped with
all of this without you.
And I'm glad I could be there for you.
But I've been thinking for a while now...
Yes?
I think it's time I moved on.
I see.
Well. if that's how you feel.
think it's best you leave.
Now.
Nessa.
this won't be the last time
we'll see each other.
Oh. I know.
Attention. passengers.
This is the final boarding
for the Emerald City Unlimited.
Doors will be closing shortly.
Please step inside and make way
for boarding passengers.
Visiting someone special?
Get a new Ozfit.
Visit the Wizard's Emporium
in downtown Emerald City.
Next.
Limited time discount
for travelers arriving today.
-Excuse me. um. my train is boarding in--
-Travel permit?
What?
All Munchkins are forbidden
to leave Munchkinland
without express written permission
of the governor.
She insisted it go
into effect immediately.
...reminder to all passengers...
Stop pushing me.
-Go!
-No. Mommy. Mommy.
-Keep your hands off my family.
-I don't wanna hear it. Munchkins.
-Move! Forward now. Munchkins.
-Go.
This is outrageous.
You cannot treat us like this.
Move along. Munchkins.
Next.
This is not the Oz I know.
-This is un-Ozian!
-Back in line.
Step back. What did I say?
Step... Munchkins. step back.
Watch your footing.
Next group. Come on. children.
-Let's move. We have to leave.
-All right. stay together!
Come along now. Keep moving.
Eyes on your children. please.
Don't worry. I'm with you.
I'll never leave you.
Don't go too fast.
What is all this?
-Watch your step.
-What are you doing?
Come. children. Quickly.
We must get out of Oz.
Don't do this. Please.
-Keep moving.
-Don't leave Oz.
Join with me. Help me fight the Wizard.
And wait for the monkeys to carry us off?
That's what happens
to animals who speak out.
And they're never seen again.
No.
Oz wouldn't be Oz without all of you.
And I know you're frightened
but this is home.
Belongs to all of us.
Elphaba.
Dulcibear.
Oh. little one.
I've missed your bear hugs.
We can't stay here.
It's become rotten.
There's only one thing left
for us to do...
escape through that tunnel
to The Place Beyond Oz.
They say The Place Beyond Oz is just...
...emptiness.
How will you survive?
How will you survive here?
No one in Oz will be happy
until you're dead.
Why would you want to stay?
I don't know.
♪ Why do I love this place
♪ That's never loved me? ♪
♪ A place that seems to be devolving ♪
♪ And even wanting to ♪
♪ But Oz is more than just a place ♪
♪ It's a promise. an idea ♪
♪ And I want to help make it come true ♪
♪ Why should a land have so much meaning ♪
♪ When dark times befall it? ♪
♪ It's only land ♪
♪ Made of dirt and rock and loam ♪
♪ It's just a place that's familiar ♪
♪ And home's just what we call it ♪
♪ But there's no place like home ♪
♪ Don't we all know ♪
♪ There's no place like home ♪
Try to understand.
We just can't fight anymore.
We have to.
♪ When you feel you can't fight anymore ♪
♪ Just tell yourself ♪
♪ There's no place like home ♪
♪ When you feel
It's not worth fighting for ♪
♪ Compel yourself ♪
♪ Because there's no place like home ♪
♪ When you want to leave ♪
♪ Discouraged and resigned ♪
♪ That's what they want you to do ♪
♪ But think how you will grieve
For all you leave behind ♪
♪ Oz belongs to you too ♪
♪ Those who would take it from you ♪
♪ Spout a lie to sell yourself ♪
♪ You go their way or go ♪
♪ It's them we'll be defeating ♪
♪ If we keep on repeating ♪
♪ There's no place like home ♪
♪ If we just keep fighting for it ♪
♪ We will win back and restore it ♪
♪ There's no place ♪
♪ Like-- ♪
Don't listen to her!
Where did he go?
At night. when I close my eyes.
I still see that green face.
I can't believe it.
-Is that you?
-Stay back!
When I was just a cub.
she snatched me
from the only home I ever knew.
You were in a cage.
If I'd have left you there.
you would never have learned to speak.
They say she's the one
who gave the monkeys wings
and gave the Wizard his spies.
Is this true?
It's true.
I cast that spell.
And I have to live with that.
If I'd have known I was being tricked.
if I'd have known why.
I would never have--
The Wizard lies. I can prove it.
And if we stand together...
Dulcibear!
Little one.
I know you'll keep fighting.
because I know you.
Thank you. Boq.
Perhaps a friendly game of cards
once I'm done working?
Whatever you say. Madame Governor.
I asked you to call me Nessa.
Remember?
Boq.
Never mind.
I'll call you when I've finished.
Now. who could have left that door open?
I did.
It's so good to see you.
Why are you here?
I've tried to keep you
out of all of this. but...
I need you.
Thought you might have come to apologize.
Apologize?
Our father died of shame.
and you didn't even bother to show up.
You might at least pretend to be sorry.
For what? He hated me.
That's a wicked thing to say.
No. it's not.
It's just the truth.
-Do you know why?
-What does it matter now?
You're right. Doesn't matter.
Because it's just us.
You're the governor. People will
listen to you. and together. we--
Why should I help you?
You fly around Oz with that book.
helping animals you've never even met.
and not once have you ever thought
to use your powers to help me.
-You never wanted my help.
-I do now!
I want to go back
to the way we were at school.
That night when Boq told me
I was beautiful.
It was the first time
I ever wore these shoes.
There was music.
And everything was still possible.
♪ That night at the Ozdust ♪
♪ Boq danced with me there ♪
♪ And it felt like he loved me then ♪
♪ That night when I felt
I was floating on air ♪
♪ I want to feel that again ♪
Make me feel that again!
Nessa. I wish there was
something I could do. but--
What are you doing?
Oh.
My shoes!
They feel like they're on fire!
I'm floating on air.
Nessa. At last.
♪ I'd always been unsure I could ♪
♪ But finally. from these powers
Something good ♪
♪ Finally. something good ♪
Thank you. Elphaba.
Nessa?
He called me Nessa! It's working!
Nessa. there's something I have to--
Look.
-You.
-Boq.
Stay back!
-It's just me. I'm not gonna hurt you.
-Boq. don't be afraid.
Elphaba just came to lift my spirits.
You did this to make her happy?
I know now anything is possible.
For both of us.
-♪ Nessa? ♪
-Yes?
♪ Uh. Nessa ♪
♪ Surely. now. I'll matter less to you ♪
♪ And you won't mind
My leaving here tonight ♪
Leaving?
♪ The moment when I read ♪
♪ Glinda's going to be wed ♪
♪ To Fiyero ♪
Glinda?
♪ Yes. Nessa. that's right ♪
♪ And I've got to go appeal to her ♪
♪ Express the way I feel to her ♪
Nessa.
I lost my heart to Glinda
the moment I first saw her.
Lost your heart?
Well. we'll see about that.
-Let him go!
-Don't come any closer!
You and your sister.
She's as wicked as you are.
Keeping me here like a prisoner.
-What are you talking about?
-I am talking about my life!
The little that's left of it.
You're gonna lose your heart
to me. I tell you!
If I have to...
I have to...
magic spell you.
There must be a magic spell in here
to capture your heart.
-Nessa. no. That's dangerous.
-What is she doing?
Stop. Nessa!
You're pronouncing the words all wrong!
W-What is she saying?
I'm going.
Ah.
Boq. what is it?
Ah. my heart.
It feels like it's-- like it's shrinking.
-Do something!
-I can't!
A spell from the Grimmerie
can never be reversed.
Boq!
This is all your fault!
If you hadn't come here--
I have to find another spell.
It's the only thing that might work.
Go. now! Go!
♪ Save him. please
Just save him ♪
♪ My poor Boq
My sweet. my brave him ♪
♪ Don't leave me till
My sorry life has ceased ♪
♪ Alone and loveless here ♪
♪ With just the girl in the mirror ♪
♪ Just her and me ♪
♪ The Wicked Witch of the East ♪
♪ We deserve each other ♪
He's sleeping now.
What about his heart?
It's all right.
He won't need one now.
The wedding...
Wait. where are you going?
All the most influential people in Oz
will be there.
It's the perfect opportunity to show them
all the truth about the Wizard.
Oh. please. Stop lying to yourself.
You're going there to find Fiyero.
but it's too late.
Nessa. I have done
everything I could for you.
and it hasn't been enough.
Nothing ever will be.
Elphaba. don't leave me!
Goodbye. Nessa.
I'm off to see the Wizard.
Where am I?
What happened?
It's all right. dearest.
You just--
What have you done?
It wasn't me. I tried to stop her.
Boq. please.
What have you done to me?
You witch!
It wasn't me. it was her! It was Elphaba!
Boq!
Ozians of the Emerald City.
today. the winds shift
and destiny unfolds before our very eyes.
Mm-hmm.
For on this night.
by the glorification of our Wizard.
Glinda the Good and Prince Fiyero Tigelaar
join hands in unification.
Do I have everything I need?
No. I need an earring. please.
Thank you.
Something oldish? Yes.
This is more than just a wedding.
It is a coronation of hope itself.
Something new...
Absolutely.
So let the very foundations of Oz
shimmer with celebratorium
for today. Oz writes a new chapter.
Rejoicify. and Oz shall shine for evermore.
Something bartered...
And something askew.
I need something askew.
Just give me a clock tick.
Elphaba Thropp. I know you're out here.
Just come in before the monkeys spot you.
Elphaba.
Galinda.
Get in. Go.
Elphie. Thank Oz you're alive.
Careful. Your dress.
I still can't believe you get around
on that old thing.
Well. we can't all come and go by bubble.
True.
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
I just wanted to come and see you.
That means a lot to me. Elphie.
-But if anyone discoverates you--
-I know.
I know.
You never saw me. I was never here.
-Do you understand?
-No. I can't bear this anymore.
-I'm taking you to see the Wizard.
-Absolutely not.
-Yes.
-No!
This is between the Wizard and I.
I understand.
But you have to trust me.
I know how to talk to him. and maybe
I could help work something out.
♪ Since I've... ♪
What?
You're done.
It's over.
I had a hunch you'd be coming back to me.
I'm not here for you. I'm here for Oz.
Elphaba. You know. you could've
just exited normally. Just use the door.
Hello?
Yes?
Don't hate me.
It's my wedding day. and you cannot
refuse a wedding wish.
Well. you can. but it's rude.
I don't have time for this.
Now. listen. You and I are gonna
go down there together.
and you are gonna admit to her guests
that you have no real power.
and that you cannot read the Grimmerie.
Why is that funny?
Elphaba. ah. I've missed you.
Can't we start again?
Yes. Please.
-Just say yes.
-No.
Don't you think I wish I could?
I would give anything to go back
to a time when I...
When I actually believed
that you were wonderful.
"The Wonderful Wizard of Oz."
No one believed in you more than I did.
But there's no going back.
And we can't move forward.
not until everyone knows what I know.
-And once they know the truth--
-They're not gonna believe it.
-How can you say that?
-Well. I'm just being straight with you.
I could tell 'em
that I'd been lying to 'em
till I'm. forgive me. blue in the face.
but wouldn't make any difference.
They're never gonna stop believing in me.
You know why?
Because they don't want to.
♪ Take it from a wise. old carny. ♪
♪ Once folks buy into your blarney! ♪
♪ It becomes the thing
They'll most hold on to ♪
♪ Once they've swallowed sham and hokum ♪
♪ Facts and logic won't unchoke em ♪
♪ They'll go on believing
What they want to ♪
♪ Show them exactly what's the score ♪
♪ They'll just believe it even more ♪
♪ Wonderful ♪
♪ They called me "Wonderful" ♪
♪ So I said. "Wonderful?
If you insist" ♪
♪ Wonderful ♪
♪ I will be "Wonderful" ♪
♪ Believe me. it's hard to resist ♪
♪ 'Cause it feels wonderful ♪
♪ They think he's wonderful ♪
♪ Hey. look who's wonderful ♪
♪ This corn-fed hick ♪
♪ Who said. "It might be keen
To build a town of green ♪
♪ And a wonderful road of yellow brick" ♪
Ow!
Bee-keek. beak-beak.
Elphie. let's be honest.
Your way hasn't worked.
But if you join forces with us.
if people see that you're with us.
they'll begin to trust you.
You'll accomplish so much more.
Yeah. Yeah. So much more.
You know. we could be like a...
like a family.
-You know. I've never really had a family.
-Lucky you.
That's why I've wanted to give
the citizens of Oz... everything.
-So you lied to them?
-No. No.
No-- Well. um.
only verbally.
But those were the lies
that they wanted to hear.
♪ The truth is not a thing of
Fact or reason ♪
♪ The truth is just
What everyone agrees on ♪
You see. back where I come from.
we got a whole lot of people
who believe all sorts of things
that aren't true.
You know what we call it?
History.
Ooh.
♪ A man's called a traitor ♪
♪ Or liberator ♪
♪ A rich man's a thief ♪
♪ Or philanthropist ♪
♪ Is one an invader ♪
♪ Or noble crusader? ♪
♪ It's all in which label
Is able to persist ♪
♪ There are precious few at ease ♪
With moral ambiguities
♪ So we act as though they don't exist ♪
It's not my best pupil.
♪ They call him "Wonderful" ♪
♪ So I am wonderful ♪
♪ He is so wonderful
It's part of his name ♪
♪ And with our help
You can be the same ♪
Come with me.
Elphie. aren't you tired of running?
Think of what we could do.
Together.
♪ Unlimited ♪
♪ Together we're unlimited ♪
♪ Together we'll be the greatest team
There's ever been ♪
♪ Elphie ♪
♪ Dreams the way we planned 'em ♪
♪ If we work in tandem ♪
♪ There's no fight we cannot win ♪
♪ At long. long. last
Receive your due ♪
♪ Long overdue ♪
♪ Elphaba. a celebration throughout Oz ♪
♪ That's all to do with you ♪
♪ Wonderful ♪
♪ They'll call you "Wonderful" ♪
♪ Come and be wonderful ♪
♪ Trust me. it's fun! ♪
♪ We will be wonderful ♪
♪ You'll make me wonderful ♪
♪ Wonderful! Wonderful! ♪
Who are you?
And why do you seek me?
Wait.
♪ It's possible I could agree ♪
♪ Wonderful ♪
♪ But this time
You have to prove yourself to me ♪
No more blaming the animals.
And the ones who've left Oz
should be free to return without fear.
Hey. with you by my side.
I'm not going to need
to blame the animals anymore.
You're not gonna need spies either. so...
set the monkeys free.
Oh. yeah? Hang on. Hang on.
Why? Why?
I think I got it. I think got it. Um...
Done.
I did it. I mean. we did it.
I'll see you two in a clock tick.
Elphie. I'm so happy.
I'm getting married.
So.
you want me to prove myself?
Oh. my gosh. Look in your hand.
How'd that get there?
It's a key. It's a key.
Aren't you surprised?
I liked that dance. That was fun.
Come here.
Now...
...I've been keeping them locked in here.
um. for their own safety.
But no need for that anymore.
Okay.
Hey. wanna come over here
and do the honors?
'Cause if you put that in here.
it'll let 'em go.
And. uh. I...
Gosh. I hope you feel good about
this whole thing 'cause. well. you've won.
but I think we all have.
Chistery.
Nothing can change
what's been done to you.
Well... what I've done.
But at least you have your freedom now.
Chistery. can you speak?
Please try.
Well.
go on.
You're free.
Fly.
Fly!
Wonderful.
Uh. well...
Hey. if you and I are gonna go down there
and greet those fancy folks.
I'd better spruce up.
Chistery. what's wrong?
Dr. Dillamond.
Dr. Dillamond. can you speak?
It's me. Elphaba.
Let me explain.
'cause this is not what it looks like.
Elphaba.
some animals cannot be trusted.
Yes.
I know that now.
And these sacred vows
are to be entered into.
not lightly. but merrily.
Elphaba.
try to understand.
No.
I'm not a bad man.
-I'm just a--
-Yes. you are.
You're a very bad man.
You once asked me
what my heart's desire was.
and I know now what that is.
And that is to fight you
till the day I die.
Run.
And do you. Glinda...
What is that horrendible sound?
Move!
Stay there.
Fiyero!
This is the work of the Wicked Witch.
She wants to kill us all!
No!
How does it feel
to have your voice taken away?
Silence. Witch.
Water.
-Lots of it. Bring water!
-Sir.
As much as you can carry.
A little help?
Please.
Thank you.
That was unpleasant.
Well. I think my trachea is otherwi--
What? What are you doing?
-Shush. you. Get in.
-What?
Get in.
Unless you want the guests
to know the truth about their wizard.
-Get in!
-Yes. yes.
Your Ozness!
Fiyero? What are you...
What is happening?
What's happened is that
these two traitors--
Not another word. Your Ozness.
Darling. have you misplaced your mind?
What are you doing?
I'm going with her.
-What?
-Let's go.
-Wait.
What?
You mean to tell me that the two of you...
This whole time?
No. It wasn't like that.
Go.
Now.
You deserve each other.
You frightened me.
For a while there.
I thought you changed.
I have changed.
This dulls the pain.
if you want a swig?
No. no. no. no! No! No!
We've got the water.
Madame.
Fools! You're too late. Get out!
How could you let this happen?
Uh. do you have a hairpin?
Thanks.
Uh. she and I had a deal.
But...
she double-crossed me.
We must smoke her out.
force her to show herself.
Without the monkeys.
I don't know how we're gonna do that.
Her sister.
Use her sister.
Spread a rumor
that her sister's in trouble.
She'll fly to her side.
and you'll have her.
Now. if you'll excuse me.
I need to lie down.
I have a bit of a headache.
A rumor won't do.
Elphaba's too smart. That's right.
These things must be done delicately.
Perhaps...
a change in the weather.
♪ Don't wish ♪
♪ Don't start ♪
♪ Wishing only wounds the heart ♪
♪ There's a girl I know ♪
♪ He loves her so ♪
♪ I'm not that... girl ♪
♪ Kiss me too fiercely ♪
♪ Hold me too tight ♪
♪ I need help believing ♪
♪ You're with me tonight! ♪
♪ My wildest dreamings
Could not foresee ♪
♪ Lying beside you ♪
♪ With you wanting me ♪
♪ Just for this moment ♪
♪ As long as you're mine ♪
♪ I've lost all resistance ♪
♪ And crossed some borderline ♪
♪ And if it turns out ♪
♪ It's over too fast. ♪
♪ I'll make every last moment last ♪
♪ As long as you're mine ♪
You're beautiful.
You don't have to lie to me.
It's not lying.
-It's...
-What is it?
It's looking at things another way.
♪ Maybe I'm brainless
Maybe I'm wise ♪
♪ But you've got me seeing ♪
♪ Through different eyes ♪
♪ Somehow I've fallen
Under your spell ♪
♪ And somehow I'm feeling ♪
♪ It's up that I fell ♪
♪ Every moment ♪
♪ As long as you're mine ♪
♪ I'll wake up my body ♪
♪ And make up for lost time ♪
♪ Say there's no future ♪
♪ For us as a pair ♪
♪ And though I may know ♪
♪ I don't care ♪
♪ Just for this moment ♪
♪ As long as you're mine ♪
♪ Come be how you want to ♪
♪ And see how bright we shine ♪
♪ Borrow the moonlight ♪
♪ Until it is through ♪
♪ And know I'll be here
Holding you ♪
♪ As long as you're mine ♪
What is it?
It's just...
For the first time. I feel... wicked.
-Take cover!
-Get inside!
Gather all your things!
Run home! Go!
Boq! Boq!
Where are you?
Come on! Come on! Inside!
Stay calm.
Move! Go!
Boq!
You can't go on living here.
-They'll find you.
-I'll be all right.
Listen.
My family has a castle in Kiamo Ko.
Never lived in it.
W-Where do you live?
In the other castle.
Okay. Of course.
I mean. it's the perfect hideout.
There's tunnels. secret passageways.
You'll be safer there.
Boq!
Where are you?
What?
Boq!
What is it?
What's wrong?
This isn't gonna make any sense. but...
There's a house...
and it's flying through the sky.
Boq!
Hey. Hey. Hey.
My sister. She's in danger.
I have to get to her.
What? I'm coming with you.
No. It's too dangerous.
Will we ever see each other again?
Elphaba. we are going
to be together always.
You can see houses flying through the sky.
but you can't see that?
This way. dear.
Goodbye. Dorothy. Bye. Dodo.
It's just that one road the whole time.
Take your time. Hurry up. darling.
Goodbye. Nessa.
What a touching display of grief.
Oh. shiz.
I scare you?
I seem to have that effect on people.
I would appreciate a moment
to say goodbye to my sister. Alone.
Of course.
Oh. Nessa.
Forgive me.
Oh. Elphaba. don't blame yourself. please.
It's dreadful. it is.
I mean... to have a house fall on you...
But accidents will happen. And...
You call that an accident?
You think cyclones just appear
out of the blue?
I don't know.
I never really thought about it--
And how dare you send that
mulish farm girl off to see the Wizard.
as if he could do anything to help?
She's lost. She's far from home.
She took a dead woman's shoes.
I had to do something.
I'm a public figure now.
People expect me to--
Lie?
Be encouraging.
Those shoes
are all I have left of my sister.
They weren't yours to give.
Yes. well.
it seems a lot of us are taking things
that don't belong to us now. aren't we?
Now. you just wait a clock tick.
It might be hard for you to comprehend
that someone like him
could choose someone like me.
but it's happened and it's real.
And you can wave that ridiculous wand
all you want.
You can't change it.
He never belonged to you.
He doesn't love you.
He never did.
He loves me.
Oh. my...
Feel better?
I do.
Good.
Me too.
Are you crazy?
Excuse me. what do you think you're doing?
Come on! Come on! Bring it!
Get back!
Get--
Here. Let's go!
You...
Please.
Where'd you get that?
What are you doing?
Come on. Let's go. greenie.
Use your hands.
Come on.
-Come on. Bring it on.
-Are you out of your mind?
-No.
-Get off of me.
Attention!
Halt in the name of the Wizard!
-Off of me.
-Let her go.
No. no. no. I almost had her.
I almost had her.
Easy.
Sorry it took us so long to get here.
Your Goodness.
You were a part of this?
Elphaba. no--
I can't believe you would stoop so low
as to use my sister's death to capture me.
I never meant it to get this far. I--
Let the green girl go.
Else explain to all Oz
how the Wizard's guards watched
while Glinda the Good was slain.
What?
-Elphaba. go.
-No.
-Not without you.
-Go!
Go.
I...
Now.
Go.
Please. protect her.
No. you're hurting him.
Stop it now.
Stop. In the name of Goodness. stop.
Can't you see he wasn't going to
harm me? He just...
He loves her.
Glinda. I am so sorry.
-Take him out to that field.
-What? No. Please.
Put him up on those poles
till he tells us where the Witch went.
Fiyero! No. Please. Let go of me.
Fiyero. Fiyero!
♪ Let his flesh not be torn
Let his blood leave no stain ♪
♪ Though they beat him
Let him feel no pain ♪
♪ Let his bones never break ♪
♪ And however they try
To destroy him ♪
♪ Let him never die
Let him never die ♪
What good is this chanting?
I don't even know what I'm reading.
♪ I don't even know what trick
I ought to try ♪
♪ Fiyero. where are you?
Already dead. or bleeding? ♪
♪ One more disaster
I can add to my generous supply? ♪
♪ No good deed goes unpunished ♪
♪ No act of charity goes unresented ♪
♪ No good deed goes unpunished
That's my new creed ♪
♪ My road of good intentions led
Where such roads always lead ♪
♪ No good deed
Goes unpunished ♪
Nessa?
Dr. Dillamond.
♪ Fiyero ♪
♪ One question haunts and hurts
Too much ♪
♪ Too much to mention ♪
♪ Was I really seeking good
Or just seeking attention? ♪
♪ Is that all good deeds are
When looked at with an ice-cold eye? ♪
♪ If that's all good deeds are
Maybe that's the reason why. ♪
♪ No good deed goes unpunished ♪
♪ All helpful urges
Should be circumvented ♪
♪ No good deed goes unpunished ♪
♪ Sure. I meant well
Well. look at what well-meant did ♪
All right. enough! So be it.
♪ So be it. then ♪
♪ Let all Oz be agreed
I'm wicked through and through ♪
♪ And since I can't succeed
Fiyero. saving you ♪
♪ I promise no good deed
Will I attempt to do again ♪
♪ Ever again ♪
♪ No good deed will I do ♪
♪ Again ♪
You have visitors.
A girl from the land of Kansas.
and three friends
she picked up along the way.
A man made of tin. another made of straw.
And a very nervous lion.
They all want something they don't have.
of course.
I'm not seeing anybody.
But these are visitors we can use.
Bring me the broomstick
of the Wicked Witch of the West...
...so I have proof that she's dead.
♪ Go and hunt her
And find her ♪
♪ And kill her ♪
Kill her!
♪ Go and hunt her
And find her ♪
♪ And kill her ♪
Kill her! Kill her! Kill her!
♪ Go and hunt her
And find her ♪
♪ And kill her ♪
Melt her! Melt her!
♪ Wickedness must be punished ♪
Kill her!
♪ Evil effectively eliminated ♪
♪ Wickedness must be punished ♪
♪ Kill the Witch! ♪
Kill her!
♪ Melt her ♪
♪ Melt the Witch ♪
And this is more than just a service
to the Wizard.
I've a personal score to settle
with Elph--
with the Witch!
♪ It's due to her I'm made of tin
Her spell made this occur ♪
♪ So for once I'm glad I'm heartless ♪
♪ I'll be heartless killing her! ♪
And I'm not the only one.
Tell them. Tell them what she did to you.
How you were just a cub...
and she cub-napped you.
♪ You see. the Lion also
Has a grievance to repay ♪
♪ If she'd let him fight his own battles
When he was young ♪
♪ He wouldn't be a coward today ♪
♪ Go and hunt her
And find her ♪
♪ And kill her ♪
Kill her! Kill her! Kill her!
Kill her!
Look.
♪ There's that beautiful girl ♪
♪ With the beautiful life ♪
♪ Such a beautiful life
Built on lies ♪
♪ 'Cause all that's required
To live in a dream ♪
♪ Is endlessly closing your eyes ♪
♪ She spins such beautiful stories ♪
♪ To sing her to sleep ♪
♪ Full of magic and glory and love ♪
♪ She's the girl in the bubble
The bright. shiny bubble ♪
♪ Blissfully floating above ♪
♪ But the truth has a way ♪
♪ Of seeping on in ♪
♪ Beneath the surface and sheen ♪
♪ And blind as you try to be ♪
♪ Eventually ♪
♪ It's hard to unsee what you've seen ♪
♪ And so that beautiful girl ♪
♪ With the beautiful life ♪
♪ Has a question that haunts her somehow ♪
♪ If she comes down from the sky
Gives the real world a try ♪
♪ Who in the world is she now? ♪
♪ And though so much of her wishes ♪
♪ That she could float on ♪
♪ And the beautiful lies never stop ♪
♪ For the girl in the bubble ♪
♪ The pink. shiny bubble ♪
♪ It's time for her bubble to pop ♪
♪ For the popular girl ♪
♪ High in the bubble ♪
♪ Isn't it high time ♪
♪ For her bubble ♪
♪ To pop? ♪
Madame. we have got to stop this.
It's gone too far.
I think Elphaba can take care of herself.
Madame.
Something has been troubling me.
About Nessa and that cyclone.
Sad.
I suppose it was just her time.
Was it?
Was it? Or did you do--
Now. you listen to me. missy.
You may be fooling the rest of Oz.
but you're not fooling me.
You wanted this from the beginning.
"Galinda."
And now you're getting what you wanted.
-No. No.
-So just do what you do best.
Smile. Wave.
And shut up.
I need your help.
♪ Wickedness must be punished ♪
♪ Brave Witch Hunters
I would join you if I could ♪
♪ Because Wickedness must be punished ♪
♪ Punished ♪
♪ But good ♪
Monkeys.
Find that Dorothy
and bring back my sister's shoes.
Oh. for Oz's sake. stop crying.
I can't listen to it anymore.
You want to get home
and see your Aunt what's-her-name again?
-Then get those shoes off your feet!
-Please stop. I'm so sorry.
I wanna go home.
They're coming for you.
Let the little girl go.
Go away.
Elphaba. you can't go on like this.
I can do whatever I want.
Haven't you heard?
I'm the Wicked Witch of the West.
Chistery. at last.
What took you so long?
What is this?
Elphie. what is that?
It's Fiyero. isn't it?
Is he...
We've seen his face for the last time.
Oh. no.
You're right.
It's time.
I surrender.
What?
Wait.
Elphaba. what are you doing?
Glinda. you can't be found here with me.
-You must go.
-Elphie. no.
Please. you must now.
Fine.
I'll go and I'll tell everyone
the truth about you.
that you're not who they say you are.
No. you can't.
-Bu--
-They'll just turn against you.
-Well. I don't care.
-Well. I do.
I need you to promise that
you won't try to clear my name.
No. What? Why would I do that?
-I'll tell them everything.
-I don't want you to do that.
You're not who they say you are.
-Please. please just--
-Listen for a minute. Just promise me!
Why would you ask me to promise that?
Because they need someone to be wicked.
so that you can be good.
♪ I'm limited ♪
Just look at me.
Not with your eyes. with theirs.
♪ I'm limited ♪
♪ And just look at you
You can do all I couldn't do ♪
♪ Glinda ♪
Here. Take it.
-What? Elphie--
-Go on.
Take it.
But you know I can't read this. I--
Well. you have to learn.
We can't let "good" be just a word.
It has to mean something.
It has to change things.
♪ Because now it's up to you ♪
For both of us.
♪ Now it's up to you ♪
You know. um...
You're the only friend I ever had.
And I've had so many friends...
...but only one that mattered.
♪ I've heard it said ♪
♪ That people come into our lives
For a reason ♪
♪ Bringing something we must learn ♪
♪ And we are led
To those who help us most to grow ♪
♪ If we let them ♪
♪ And we help them in return ♪
♪ Well. I don't know
If I believe that's true ♪
♪ But I know I am who I am today ♪
♪ Because I knew you ♪
♪ Like a comet pulled from orbit
As it passes a sun ♪
♪ Like a stream that meets a boulder
Halfway through the wood ♪
♪ Who can say if I've been changed
For the better? ♪
♪ But because I knew you ♪
♪ I have been changed for good ♪
♪ It well may be
That we will never meet again ♪
♪ In this lifetime ♪
So let me say before we part
♪ So much of me is made
Of what I learned from you ♪
♪ You'll be with me ♪
♪ Like a handprint on my heart ♪
♪ And now whatever way
Our stories end ♪
♪ I know you have rewritten mine ♪
♪ By being my friend ♪
♪ Like a ship blown from its mooring
By a wind off the sea ♪
♪ Like a seed dropped by a sky bird
In a distant wood ♪
♪ Who can say if I've been changed
For the better? ♪
♪ But because I knew you ♪
♪ Because I knew you ♪
♪ I have been changed for good ♪
♪ And just to clear the air ♪
♪ I ask forgiveness for the things
I've done you blame me for ♪
♪ But then I guess
We know there's blame to share ♪
♪ And none of it seems to matter anymore ♪
-♪ Like a comet pulled from orbit ♪
-♪ Like a ship blown from its mooring ♪
-♪ As it passes a sun ♪
-♪ By a wind off the sea ♪
♪ Like a stream that meets a boulder ♪
♪ Like a seed dropped
By a bird in the wood ♪
♪ Halfway through the wood ♪
♪ Who can say if I've been changed ♪
♪ For the better? ♪
♪ I do believe I have been changed
For the better ♪
♪ And because I knew you ♪
♪ Because I knew you ♪
♪ I have been changed ♪
♪ For good ♪
Come on. Come on. Quick.
No one can know you were here.
-You stay here.
-What?
Everything's gonna be fine.
I love you.
I love you too.
♪ And Goodness knows ♪
♪ The Wicked's lives are lonely ♪
♪ Goodness knows ♪
♪ The Wicked die alone ♪
Oh. Elphie...
Miss Glinda.
She's dead.
-Do you have her broomstick?
-No.
But I do have something else
that belonged to her.
It was a keepsake. She told me herself.
It belonged to her mother.
This belonged to...
her mother?
So Elphaba was yours all along.
That's why she had such powers.
she was a child of both worlds.
Oh. my Lord.
What have I done?
You have caused great harm.
Which is why you will be leaving Oz.
Today.
Did you hear what I said?
And what... what will I tell people?
Make something up.
You're good at that.
Excuse me.
Hello.
What? What do you want?
Look out your window.
Come on. You don't wanna miss this.
Excuse me. please.
Don't leave without us.
Please. I wanna go home.
I swear. it never ends with that girl.
The Wizard is taking
a permanent leave of absence.
Not a rumor. a fact.
The kind that is true.
Glinda. dear.
Can you not find it in your heart
t-to forgive me?
As Oz is my witness.
I can see now how truly good you are.
Actually. I'm not. Not yet.
But just think. Madame.
We have so many cages.
and all recently vacated.
You'll have your pick.
Although I can't imagine
you'll hold up very well.
I mean. my personal opinion is
you do not have what it takes.
I hope you prove me wrong.
I doubt you will.
What are you doing? Let go of me. Let--
♪ Good news ♪
♪ She's dead ♪
♪ The Witch of the West is dead ♪
♪ The Wickedest Witch there ever was ♪
♪ The enemy of all of us here in Oz ♪
♪ Is dead ♪
♪ Good news ♪
Whoo! Yep.
Well. this has been fun.
As you can imagine.
I have much to attend to
with the Wizard's unexpected departure.
So if there are no further questions.
I'm gonna go.
Glinda.
Is it true you were her friend?
What?
Sorry. one sec.
Is it true you were her friend?
Friend?
Yes.
I-I mean. I did know her.
That is.
our paths did cross.
At school.
Wait.
I have something more to say.
Fellow Ozians.
All Ozians.
Yes. come out.
Wherever you are. come out.
Friends.
Because I don't see any enemies here.
We have been through a frightening time.
And there will be other times
and other things that frighten us.
But if you'll let me...
I'd like to try to help.
To change things.
I'd like to try to be...
Glinda the Good.
It worked.
They all think you're dead.
Fiyero?
See?
Good as new.
You saved my life.
You're beautiful.
You don't have to lie to me.
It's not lying.
It's...
It's looking at things in another way.
Time to go.
I wish that
Glinda could know we're alive.
But I know she can't.
No one can ever know.
♪ Who can say ♪
♪ If I've been changed for the better? ♪
-♪ But because I knew you ♪
-♪ Because I knew you ♪
♪ No one mourns the Wicked ♪
♪ Because I knew you ♪
♪ I have been changed ♪
♪ No one mourns the Wicked ♪
♪ Wicked ♪